<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<books Load="Merge">
    <book ID="LargerFolk_WeightSounds" Title="WeightSounds">
        <page>{{emote|*Huff.*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Huff.*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Huff, puff.*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Haaaah...*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Wheeze.*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Whoof.*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Haaaah, haaaah...*}}</page>
    </book>
    <book ID="LargerFolk_BellySounds" Title="BellySounds">
        <page>{{emote|*Gurgle.*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Grooooooan...*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Streeeeeetch...*}}</page>
        <page>{{emote|*Grumble.*}}</page>
    </book>

    <book ID="LargerFolk_WeightReport" Title="{{W|Classification and Process of Excess Consumption, 1st Edition}}" Format="Auto" Margins="1,2,2,2">
        <page>{{c|from the desk of Dardi, edited by {{m|Q Girl}}.}}
        [[{{W|Preface - A record of study for professionals and "enthusiasts" alike.}}]]

The body is an alarmingly complex artifact, which one may study for as long it lasts without plumbing every depth of its peculiar quirks.

It is fortunate that my area of special interest in biology is quite particular, that I might hope to compile a comprehensive interpretation on its workings- The phenomenon of "soft flesh". 

Within, I have compiled the fruits of my research and personal experimentation in the field.

On {{m|Q Girl}}'s request I have passed the manuscript by her for "adding flavour" to some descriptions, though I'm unsure what such a task entails.
        </page>
        <page>[[{{C|Process - Intake and Effort}}]]
The common understanding of the metabolic process is accurate, though incomplete.

It is true that increased food intake promotes the accumulation of soft flesh, as energy in excess of that required for bodily process is stored for later in fatty deposits, later used when that energy is required.

But, with careful examination, we can point to specific behaviours and factors that lead to this phenomenon. 

Simple sustenance meals cooked with whatever is available generally keep the body stable rather than than expanding it. Decadent meals with many ingredients, however, certainly pave the road toward a wider waistline.

The worst offender of all is snacks. If you wish to avoid outgrowing your recycling suit in your travels, it's wise to stick to home cooking and avoid the temptation of grazing on endless treats, particularly meat and sweets. 

Many a traveler on the plains of Qud has come upon a well-stocked larder left unguarded, and later found the doorway not quite so forgiving as when they entered.

If one feels they've packed on a bit more than comfortable, the sad truth is that exercise and an empty stomach is the only credible option. Only when no energy is being received from food intake does the body start to use up its excess stock.
        </page>
        <page>[[{{C|Classification - Fat, Fatter, Fattest}}]]
While the average inhabitant of Qud tends to stay more or less within the lower range of adiposal accumulation, the amount of soft flesh clinging to the body can be described as fitting into one of several distinct stages.

In my time as a Food-Tinker I've had the opportunity to witness first-hand the changes ones caloric intake can have upon the body (particularly my own), and have compiled my notes upon the different stages of development here. 

This system of classification should be taken with a grain of salt, as it is based only upon my observations of certain characteristics common to bodies harbouring similar levels of excess softness rather than any quantitative physiological marker.

As the process of determining the total usable energy contained in a given substance is as yet unknown to me or my associates, the intake threshold corresponding to each stage (assuming no exercise) will be measured in Starapples.

[[{{W|Lean - 0-24 Starapples}}]]

The most common stage. Ranges from toned to a slight clinging softness, particularly around the midsection. At this stage, the more pressing concern should be starvation.

[[{{W|Fat - 25-59 Starapples}}]]

Somewhat common as well, though still takes some by surprise as evidenced by their ill-fitting apparel. A significant softness coats the body, quite pleasant to the touch.

Secondary attributes start to collect more visible softness, particularly the lower body (and the chest, in some cases). The face rounds out into a somewhat cherubic image, filling out the oft-poeticized "double chin".

Minimal issues are observed, but one may want to consider widening doors and reinforcing furniture sooner rather than later.
        </page>
        <page>[[{{C|Classification (Cont.)}}]]
[[{{W|Obese - 60-99 Starapples}}]]

Rare, but not inconceivable. At this stage the body has grown large enough that the internal framework has some difficulty controlling it, and unavoidable issues present themselves.

Fatty deposits are swollen to twice the size of a lean or even fat individual, manifesting as a pendulous gut, pillow-like haunches and ham hock-like piles surrounding the upper arms.

A good tailor is a must. Decent clothing is hard to come by, and a hearty appetite is a sorry reason to lose it. If decency rather than defense is one's concern, the depth to which one's belly hangs at this stage should safely cover anything untoward.

Antagonistic encounters with architecture are an inevitability rather than a distant worry, account for some struggle time should an escape through a narrow passage be needed- the obese physique is ill-suited to adventure.

At this stage the body exerts itself much more with each movement, and mobility is impeded. With this extra effort comes the huffing and puffing associated, one may hear the panting of particularly heavyset traveller long before they appear.

[[{{W|Immobile - 100+ Starapples}}]]

An exceedingly uncommon stage, seldom (if ever) reached unless a concerted effort is made to expand the body as much as possible.

The hypothesized existence of this stage is based upon following the vectors of mobility impact across stages to point to a size at which movement would become impossible for a given creature.
        </page>
        <page>
While I haven't met anything fitting this description, an associate of mine (who will go unnamed for her privacy) has excitedly described to me her imaginings of what it may be like.

Such fantasies cannot be used as a basis for a scientific paper, so I will refrain from relaying them here. 

However, my associate has expressed an interest in attempting to reach this stage herself, so perhaps a future edition will include a more comprehensive look at the full spectrum of softness.
        </page>
    </book>


</books>
